# Frank Arregger-Powell

I am a data professional with a proven track record in delivery of modeling and analytical solutions that have made significant contributions in the organizations I've worked for. I have a masters in green chemistry, energy and the environment from Imperial College London and 5+ years of experience in data science and data analytics roles; working in teams using multiple platforms including Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud Platform and coding in SQL, R and Python. At this stage in my career, I am looking to build on the knowledge I have gained to have a positive and lasting impact on the environment. I would like to combine my technical and team working abilities to transform the way data is used to solve complex problems.

**EXPERIENCE** 

## **CDP**, London — Senior Data Analyst

April 2021 - PRESENT

A not-for-profit organization that runs a global disclosure system for investors, companies, cities, states and regions to disclose and manage their environmental impacts.

Data Analytics Team

- Developed the Full Greenhouse Gas Emissions dataset which includes reported and estimated emissions and energy data using physical and economic models.
- Managed a team of 5 data analysts in an agile framework to produce one of the worlds largest datasets of corporate emissions.
- Worked on statistical economic models predicting emissions and energy for companies in all sectors.
- Developed and produced a Scope-3 report displaying companies supply-chain emissions and averages across sectors and activities.
- Estimated scope 1, 2 & 3 emissions for companies

### **Bulb**, London — Data Scientist

April 2019 - March 2021

A startup renewable energy supplier looking to lower carbon emissions and lower the cost of energy bills.

Operations Pod

- Built an alerting framework using Grafana to notify our team where there were discrepancies in information being sent between suppliers.
- Delivered £2m in extra income over 6 months for a top-up campaign which targeted members who were in debt but could pay.

4/139 Queens Drive, Lyall Bay, Wellington, 6022 0225276555 farreggerpowell@gmail.com

#### **SKILLS**

#### Technical:

SQL, Python, R, Azure DevOps, Google Cloud Platform, BigQuery, DBT, Looker, Power BI, Excel and Microsoft Office Suite, Grafana, GitHub, Mode Analytics

### **Business:**

Emissions modeling, Regulatory reporting, Strategic Planning, Team Development, Analytical Insight, Agile Methodology, Automation, Statistical analysis

## **INTERESTS**

I try to read as much as I can to develop a better understanding of the world whether that's history, fiction or political books. I continuously improve my coding skills by doing leetcode challenges and learning new technologies. I play football regularly for a few different teams across London having played a lot when I was younger and throughout university. I have a passion for music and ran a jazz radio show on a community radio station in North London.

- Automated many operational processes to reduce the manual work by 1000s of hours per week.
- Reported most of Bulbs RFIs (requests for information) from OFGEM on regulatory requirements and issues.
- Built and adapted a price change communication data model which would be used to email 1.7 million people about upcoming price changes

# $\textbf{Bulb,} \, \mathsf{London} - \mathit{Energy} \, \mathit{Specialist}$

April 2017 - 2019

- Provided data and insight for the experience team allowing anyone in the team to understand real time data by creating reports.
- Managed our relationship with National Grid Metering making sure the process was running smoothly for our gas meters

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Imperial College London**, London — Green Chemistry Energy and the Environment

October 2015 - October 2016

Computational Biochemistry Lab

Toolkit: Chimera, Guassian, Excel, Linux

- Completed novel research into photosynthetic bacteria aiming to alter efficiency through mutation to aid development of solar powered technology.
- Completed a viva on my dissertation and presented it in a large lecture theater to professors and fellow academics

# **University of Sheffield**, Sheffield — Chemistry

September 2012 - July 2015